Based on an absurd but true story
Stockholm is a crime, comedy film directed by Robert Budreau.
Based on the extraordinary true story of the European city’s 1973 bank heist and hostage crisis
that was documented in the 1974 New Yorker article “The Bank Drama” by Daniel Lang.
The events grasped the world’s attention when the hostages bonded with their captors and turned against
the authorities, giving rise to the psychological phenomenon known as “Stockholm Syndrome.”
Lars Nystrom, played by Ethan Hawke.
Bianca Lind, played by Noomi Rapace.
Gunnar Sorensson, played by Mark Strong.
Chief Mattsson, played by Christopher Heyerdahl.
Klara Mardh, played by Bea Santos.
Elov Eriksson, played by Mark Rendall.
Stockholm (known as The Captor in some countries) is a 2018 crime
comedy-drama film written, produced and directed by Robert Budreau.
It stars Ethan Hawke, Noomi Rapace, Mark Strong, Christopher
Heyerdahl, Bea Santos and Thorbjørn Harr.
The film premiered at the Tribeca Film Festival on April 19, 2018, and
was released on April 12, 2019, by Smith Global Media.
The film is loosely based on the true story of the 1973
bank heist and hostage crisis in Stockholm.
The film explores themes of stockholm syndrome, hostage, 1970s, based
on true story, based on magazine, newspaper or article.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.